

Akmal Muzakki Bakir

Jl. Babakan Radio No. 6 Citeureup, Dayeuhkolot, Kab. Bandung 40256

Hello, I'm Akmal, a programmer who currently focuses on artificial intelligence, machine learning, deep learning, and data manipulation. Ah, and I'm also doing UI/UX design and web development for my projects too!

ABOUT

I am a Data Science student at Telkom University. I was born in Jakarta on August 25, 2003. I am experienced in teaching basic mathematics and logic programming. I'm interested in machine learning and artificial intelligence, and I'm currently deepening that knowledge. In addition, some of the sciences that I often learn are data science, data analysis, data visualization, and deep learning. Some of the sciences I like to learn are simple backend and frontend science.

EXPERIENCE

StudyGez / Math Tutor

June 2021 - December 2021, Online

One of the ways I learned was, by sharing my knowledge with others, then I planned to become a math tutor at one of the start-ups to re-hone my math skills. My teaching system was online at that time, because of the covid-19 pandemic.

Ganesha Operation / Math Tutor

November 2020 - April 2021, Online

One of the ways I learned was, by sharing my knowledge with others, then I planned to become a math tutor at one of the start-ups to re-hone my math skills. My teaching system was online at that time, because of the covid-19 pandemic.

ISLAH LDK Al-Fath Telkom University / Lead of Division Coding

August 2022 - November 2022, Onsite

Coding stands for Consumption and Funding, in this division, I want to get new experience in managing finances. In this division, I served as division chairman.

Faculty of Informatics / Assistant Lecturer Discrete Math

March 2023 - July 2023, Onsite

I used to be an assistant lecturer in discrete mathematics. This job is done to fill spare time during college. I took this position because I felt I was a good fit in the field.

Faculty of Informatics / Assistant Lecturer Programming Algorithm

March 2023 - July 2023, Onsite

I used to be an assistant lecturer in programming algorithms. This job is done to fill spare time during college. I took this position because I felt I was a good

fit in the field.

Student Association of Telkom University / Staff Ministry of

Professional Development

March 2023 - Present, Hybrid

I once joined a campus organization, namely the student association, with a position as a staff of the professional development division. Here I get a lot of new knowledge about professions that will be in high demand in the future.

EDUCATION

MAN 1 Kota Bekasi / IPA

July 2018 - July 2021, Bekasi

I once went to school at MAN 1 Bekasi City, majoring in Science. My school is quite far from home, but I love going to school there, because there are many memorable experiences such as participating in various competitions, and making friends with frequency.

Telkom University / Data Science (GPA: 3.87)

August 2021 - Present, Bandung

Currently, I am studying at Telkom University majoring in S1 Data Science. This department is fairly new because considering the need for data in the future is getting higher. I find it a good fit in this field because I like to play around data and logic.

PROJECT

Predict Salary 🔼

Machine learning website to predict your Salary according to your country, lecturer, job status, work, gender, and experience.

Recommendation System

Movie recommendation system app from tmdb movie database with sentiment analysis, based on machine learning.



Application designed for rental housing search, based on UI/UX design.

ACHIEVEMENT

3rd Winner of District-Level Math KSM

2020

Finalist of 31st LMNas UGM

2019

Finalist of OPTIKA UIN Jakarta

2020

SKILLS

Programming Language

- Python
- Java
- Go
- Javascript
- Kotlin
- HTML/CSS

Until now, I am used to using Python programming language, because I dream of becoming a data scientist or at least a career in data, but in some cases, I also use javascript, html, and css programming languages to design website interfaces as a place for me to put my portfolio, I have also used go and javascript languages as rest APIs or backend tests, In addition, I use Java and Kotlin to design mobile apps to learn new material in android studio.

Databases

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

I can implement SQL languages including DDL and DML. The database I'm used to is MySQL, but in some cases, I also use PostgreSQL because of its language structure that is almost close to SQL language and many more accessible features than MySQL. I've also learned MongoDB, but it's still a basic level.

Design

- Figma
- Adobe After Effect
- Filmora
- Canva
- Wordpress

In figma, I once made a UI of a rented residence application, in adobe after effect, about a few years ago, I once made a creative opening video together with filmora. For small design projects, I usually use Canva. And a few years ago, I once created a blog on wordpress with the theme of travel about life.

Basic Skills

- Machine Learning
- Data Analysis
- Data Engineer
- Deep Learning
- Frontend

I have several portfolios that I store on github, among some of these portfolios, most of the portfolios that I keep are related to data, it can be known because the domain file is jupyter, some of these projects are based on machine learning, data analysis, data engineering, and deep learning.

Tools

- Git
- Github
- Rapid Miner
- VS Code
- Data Spell (Pycharm Alternative)
- Data Grip
- Intellij IDEA (Netbeans Alternative)
- Tableau
- Power BI
- Android Studio

Some of the tools that I use are tools that are prioritized for data management, I also use tools that are specifically for designing mobile applications such as Android Studio, and Intellij Idea

Other Skills

- Problem Solving
- Math and Logic
- Statistics and Probability
- Microsoft and Google Tools
- Basic Azure and AWS
- Backend and API

Some of the other skills I have are related to my experience in the field.

CONTACT

Portofolio

- Akmal Muzakki Bakir (LinkedIn)
- akmalmzkki.github.io (Website)
- akmalmzkki 🔼 (Github)

Email

- akmalmzkki@student.telkomuniversity.ac.id
- akmalm2003@gmail.com

More

- @akmal_mzkki (Instagram)
- 088292113638 (Whatsapp)